there to to kind of answer and give some
insights around electrolytes though
there's absolutely a relationship
between trt and magnesium uh trt will
deplete magnesium at a faster rate
because testosterone uh depletes
magnesium as part of its metabolism
cycle so the higher your testosterone is
the higher your requirement for
magnesium I think that the higher your
testosterone is the higher your
requirements for a lot of nutrients are
and I think it's very important that if
a man wants to optimize and increase his
testosterone up to the healthiest
physiological level he could possibly
have he also needs to provide himself
with the best quality nutrition and fuel
across a broad range of micronutrients
so I would be looking at all
electrolytes there are some great Trace
mineral supplements that you can get but
I think that particularly if someone's
predisposed to anxiety and they train a
lot I would look at magnesium before
looking at other things because a lot of
people I don't I don't think the
argument that everyone's deficient in
magnesium is evidence-based I think that
that's very good marketing from people
who sell magnesium but I do think that
if someone is looking to supplement with
electrolytes I think on trt especially
if they train a lot magnesium is a good
place to start um glycinate or B
glycinate is the best option because
it's the most tolerated in higher Doses
and a lot of guys do get maximal
benefits from magnesium glycinate at
higher doses than 400 milligram a day
some sometimes looking at 3 to 500 migr
twice a day but if they use other forms
like citrate that will result in a
laxative effect magnesium trate
make you uh so it's important to
use magnesium glycinate if we're going
to be pushing the dose up more than 400
milligram day
[Music]